Jake Pearson

5038001121 | jake.pearson.1694@gmail.com | 515 East Broadway 508, Eugene OR 97401, USA, Eugene, OR

Summary

Personable and energetic student with years of on the job customer service experience in many different areas. Studying computer science for a bachelors in science. Excellent interpersonal skills along with multitasking abilities. Proactive and open mindset, able to predict and complete tasks before they become critical. In-School coding experience plus workplace Excel experience.

Experience

Production Technician | 01/2021 - 09/2021 | VetSource USA | Portland, Oregon

Helped implement new inventory management system that included more frequent inventorying of chemical solution stock levels to ensure uninterrupted lab services

Oversee staff of eight lab technicians, training them in sample preparation and lab techniques

Perform routine lab equipment calibration and function checks to ensure accuracy

Follow all lab protocols, sanitation standards, and company policies to ensure safety and efficiency

Play with animals too obviously!

Server Assistant/Host/Food Runner | 01/2022 - Present | BJ'S Restaurant & Brewhouse | Eugene, OR

Provide excellent service and recommendations to guests

Deliver exceptional customer service through extensive menu knowledge

Carefully hand wash, rinse and sanitize delicate china and stemware for fine dining restaurant Maintain a clean, organized working environment

Play an integral role in customer service and overall sales numbers

Work alongside a team of 40+ people

Respond quickly to customer inquiries

Line Cook/Prep Cook | 09/2021 - 01/2022 | Pastini | Eugene, OR

Created stock and prepared delicately balanced soups from scratch

Ensure items are well-stocked for each shift

Assumed management of and reinforced kitchen safety and sanitation practices, rapidly increasing health inspection score to A+rating

Proficient in preparing ingredients, including cutting meat and chopping/peeling vegetables and fruit

Tracked and reported inventory, reducing food waste and saving hundreds each month

Retail Sales Associate | 06/2020 - 09/2020 | Lowe's Home Improvement | Hillsboro, Oregon

Play an integral role in customer service and overall sales numbers Clean up minor spills quickly and safely

Maximize positive customer service experience

Assist customers in finding specific items

Consistently meet and surpass monthly ordering and sales goals assigned by Director of Operations and General Manager

Front Crew Member | 04/2018 - 06/2019 | Dairy Queen | Portland, Oregon

Provide customers with the best possible face-to-face service

Keep track of money in my till throughout my shift

Ensure the dining room was up to service and clean for guests

Skills

Data entry, WORD, Excel, Customer service

Education

Compter Science | Lane Community College ~ Ongoing | 06/2024 | Eugene, OR

Currently completing courses in computer science, high-level discrete algebra, and statistics.